hey Breet andas here going to go over
the wrong way and the right way to do
rack pulls so a lot of times I'll see a
video and I'll um I'll watch someone do
like a 900lb rack pull but then you you
know they don't really deadlift 900 lb
they can only deadlift say 600 lb and
there's a 300 lb discrepancy there and
the reason why that happens is because
they're not doing the rack pull the same
way they deadlift the kinematics are
totally different up top top so if you
want to maximize the transfer of the
rack pull to the deadlift and you're
looking to work your posterior chain you
need to do the rack pull in a specific
manner so here's what I see a lot of
guys do they will line up far away from
the bar and they will bring their knees
you know close to the bar and kind of
squat the weight up so this way it's a
more quad dominant lift they're
squatting it
up and then they come down and stick the
knees out like that and that's not a
good way to do the rack pull because as
I mentioned before you want it to match
what it looks like when you do a real
deadlift when you do a real deadlift as
you get right here um your knees have
already extended and it's more
straight-legged right here right here is
just pushing the hips forward so if you
want to um maximize the transfer you
need to almost think of it like a
partial straight leg deadlift
so I line up to where my knees are
almost touching the
bar and then from
here so it'll be a little EAS easier to
see from the side view so I'm going to
show you from the side what that looks
like okay wrong
way line up far away from the bar so
there's this distance and I push my
knees forward to it so the wrong way
right here
[Music]
okay see my knee angle and then the
right
way line up close to the
bar my Tios are going to stay vertical
and I sit back like that so I'm only
moving hips back shins stay in the same
place from here
[Music]
so I sit back okay that's the right way
to do rack pull